

online

languages

english (proficient) mandarin

programming

Python, JavaScript, Java, Ruby, C, Perl

technical skills

HTML & CSS, LATEX, Linux System Administration of Tan Jing Shan, Shawn⋈ 5 Jalan Asas, Singapore 678763

✓ DOB: 1987/12/17 (+65) 93877026

about

I'm currently a Masters student at the University of Montreal, where I work at the Montreal Institute of Learning Algorithms (MILA). I enjoy working on machine learning projects, and keeping up with the latest in neural networks research. I maintain a blog where I write about my machine learning projects.

research interests

Semantics3

artificial intelligence, recurrent neural networks, machine learning, reinforcement learning, graphical models, natural language processing, data mining

bayes model built using the Lucene index.

Web Information Retrieval and NLP Group (WING), NUS

experience

2013-2014

2010-2012

2016-present	Montreal Institute for Learning Algorithms, University of Montreal	Masters Student
	Working on deep learning research.	
2014-2016	Speech Recognition Group, National University of Singapore	Research Assistant
	Working on the machine learning aspects of speech recognition usin	g neural networks,
	with applications to speaker adaptation and noise robustness.	

- Classification of products into a hierarchical taxonomy using a cascading naive
 - Name equivalency model used as part of the disambiguation process to determine if two product names are referring to the same thing.

Software/Data Engineer

Undergraduate researcher

• Experimented with using conditional random fields for attribute extraction from product names.

	Did two undergraduate research projects (see next page)	
2008-2009	Singapore Armed Forces	Manpower Officer
	Administrative position managing National Servicemen	
01-06 2007	RHyMeS Center, Ngee Ann Polytechnic	Research/Teaching Assistant

- Provided technical support for students working on the RHyMeS project.
- Facilitated workshops on using the RHyMeS SDK and API.
- Taught students working on their projects how to use the Java Swing UI API

education

2016-present Masters of Computer Science

University of Montreal

2009-2012 **Bachelors of Computing (BComp)** National University of Singapore

Major in Computer Science - Upper 2nd Class Honours Special Programme in Computing (Turing Programme)

Focus Area: Artificial Intelligence

CAP: 4.39 / 5

2004-2007 **Diploma in Information Technology**

Ngee Ann Polytechnic, Singapore

Specialisation in Software Engineering - Diploma with Merit

GPA: 3.8 / 4

2003 **GCE '0' Levels**

Mayflower Secondary School, Singapore

projects

10 2014 Neural Turing Machines implementation in Theano

Implementation of system described in "Neural Turing Machines." by Alex Graves, Greg

Wayne, and Ivo Danihelka.

2012 **Predicting Web 2.0 Thread Updates**

A method to estimate arrival times of new posts to forum discussion threads and an evaluation metric for measuring the effectiveness of an incremental crawler of a site with

time-sensitive data.

04 2012 Focused Web Crawling using Markov Decision Processes

Using the least-squares policy iteration algorithm and some heuristics to perform focused

crawling. For CS4246R AI for Planning and Decision Making (Research Project)

2010 - 2011 grabsmart: A User-centric Web Information Extraction System

An integrated system that allows users to easily select portions of a page to extract, and

subsequently extracts the data in a manner that is robust to site layout changes.

04 2011 LSPI Tetris Agent

Application of the least-squares policy iteration algorithm to play Tetris as part of the CS3243 Introduction to Artificial Intelligence course. The agent can complete 100,000

lines on average, and up to a maximum of about a million lines.

organisations

2010-2012 **NUS Hackers** Coreteam Member (Member of Executive Committee)

Duties include facilitating NUS Hacker activities: Hack & Roll 2012, Friday Hacks (a weekly tech talk), and maintaining the download.nus.edu.sg mirror service.

2003-2012 **Singapore Scouts Association**

Assistant Venture Scout Leader

Attached to the Mayflower Secondary School Boy Scouts Group. Duties a include facilitating camps, weekly meetings, and mentoring both scouts and ventures.